Guide to the Murray Bundy Photographs of Musicians circa 1930s-1940s
Washington State University Libraries Manuscripts, Archives, and Special Collections
Murray Bundy Photographs of Musicians
circa 1930s-1940s
Washington State University Libraries, Manuscripts, Archives and Special Collections
PC 88
Bundy, Murray Wright.
1 box 34 items
This collection consists of 34 black and white photographs of musical artists.
Dr. Murray Wright Bundy served as the Washington State College English Department Head, three time Phi Beta Kappa President, and an English professor from 1928 to 1956 before he retired. The Bundy Reading Room in Avery Hall is named in his honor.
This collection consists of 34 black and white photographs of musical artists. A number of the photographs are personally autographed to Dr. Bundy and his wife, Mary Sarah Rappleye Bundy, or to two of his daughters, Barbara Jean Bundy and Eleanor Mabel Bundy.
This collection is open and available for research use.
This collection is indexed under the following headings in the online catalog. Researchers desiring materials about related topics, persons, or places should search the catalog using these headings.
Musicians -- Photographs.
Music; Photographs
- Mozart Boys Choir of Vienna. The Metropolitan Musical Bureau, Inc. 18 March 1939. Signed by each of the twenty members., 1 item (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Astrid Varnay, Prima Dona Soprano. Metropolitan Opera Association, 1945. Signed by Astrid Varnay., 1 item (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Helen Jepson, Leading Soprano. Metropolitan Opera Company, 1938. Signed by Helen Jepson., 1 item (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Rose Bampton, Leading Soprano. Metropolitan Opera Company, undated. Signed by Rose Bampton., 1 item (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Jennie Tourel, Mezzo Soprano, undated., 1 item (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Marian Anderson, Contralto, undated. One signed by Marian Anderson., 2 items (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Anna Kaskas, Contralto. Metropolitan Opera Association. One undated, one dated 23 March 1945. Signed by Anna Kaskas., 2 items (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Kathryn Meisle, Contralto. Metropolitan Opera Association, 17 March 1941. Signed by Kathryn Meisle., 1 item (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Igor Gorin, Baritone, undated. One signed by Igor Gorin., 2 items (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Robert Weede, Baritone, 1943. Signed by Robert Weede., 1 item (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Walter Cassel, Baritone. Metropolitan Opera Association, 1946. Signed by Walter Cassel., 1 item (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Lansing Hatfield, Baritone, undated. Signed by Lansing Hatfield., 1 item (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Paul Robeson, Bass-Baritone, 1941. Signed by Paul Robeson., 1 item (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Ethel Bartlett and Rae Robertson, Duo-Pianists, undated. Signed by Ethel Bartlett and Rae Robertson., 1 item (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Victor Babin and Vitya Vronsky, Duo-Pianists, 2 May 1949. Signed by Victor Babin and Vitya Vronsky., 1 item (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Eugene List, Pianist, 5 December 1939. Signed by Eugene List., 1 item (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Dalies Frantz, Pianist, undated. Signed by Dalies Frantz., 1 item (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Joseph Hofmann, Pianist, 1938. Signed by Joseph Hofmann., 1 item (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Pierre Pasquier (viola), Jean Pasquier (violin), Etienne Pasquier (cello), The Pasquier Trio, March 1947. Signed by each of the three members., 1 item (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Gasper Cassado, Cellist, 19 January 1940. The Metropolitan Musical Bureau, Inc. Signed by Gasper Cassado., 1 item (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Joseph Schuster, Cellist, undated., 3 items (Box 1, Folder 21)
- William Primrose, Violist, February 1946. Signed by William Primrose., 1 item (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Erica Morin, Violinist, 1945. Signed by Erica Morin., 1 item (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Zino Francescatti, Violinist, December 1940. Signed by Zino Francescatti., 1 item (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Jascha Heifetz, Violinist. View of his hands and violin, undated., 2 items (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Dimitri Mitropoulos, Conductor, Minneapolis Symphony Orchestra, undated., 1 item (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Minneapolis Symphony Orchestra, Dimitri Mitropoulos Conducting, undated., 2 items (Box 1, Folder 27)